He Sits. He Stays. He Shoots. He Scores.
Air Bud is a comedy, family film directed by Charles Martin Smith.
A lonely boy befriends a stray dog who has a natural talent for basketball and together they experience
the highs and lows of life as their friendship remains solid through a series of escapades.
Josh Framm, played by Kevin Zegers.
Jackie Framm, played by Wendy Makkena.
Norm Snively, played by Michael Jeter.
Arthur Chaney, played by Bill Cobbs.
Judge Cranfield, played by Eric Christmas.
Larry Willingham, played by Brendan Fletcher.
Air Bud is a 1997 sports comedy-drama film directed by Charles Martin Smith.
An international co-production of the United States and Canada, the film stars Kevin Zegers as a young boy who
befriends a runaway Golden Retriever (portrayed by Buddy) with a unique ability to play basketball.
Air Bud received mixed reviews but was a commercial success, grossing $4 million in its opening
weekend and totaling $27.8 million in its run against an estimated $3 million budget.
It was followed by a direct sequel, Air Bud: Golden Receiver, in 1998, and spawned
a film franchise that includes the spin-off series Air Buddies.
The film explores themes of sports, clown, basketball, dog, golden retriever.
The tone is lighthearted.